<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Program on QCrypt 2020</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/</link><description>Recent content in Program on QCrypt 2020</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Break + Q&amp;A + networking</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/__break/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/__break/</guid><description>Lunch and Coffee is served over in our virtual Meet &amp;amp; Greet Room . The speakers from the last session are available for an after-talk chat at the tables.</description></item><item><title>Business Meeting &amp; Best Student Paper Price (Chair: Qiang Zhang)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/business/</guid><description>Program (5 min) Qiang Zhang, SC chair: Summary of SC activitiesfrom Oct 2019 – Aug 2020 SC slides (5 min) Fred Dupuis, PC chair: # submissions, acceptance rate, PC members PC slides (5 min) Christian Schaffner, Local chair: # participants, stats 2020 (5 min) Serge Fehr, Future chair: preview of QCrypt 2021 2021 (15 min) Open Discussion
Around 15:05: Best Student Paper Award
Best Student Paper Awards Award slides Theory Congratulations to Jiayu Zhang for Succinct Blind Quantum Computation Using a Random Oracle</description></item><item><title>Closing</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/close/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/close/</guid><description>Goodbye, folks! See you next year in person in Amsterdam!</description></item><item><title>Contributed Talks 1a: Quantum MPC (Chairs: Omar Fawzi and Carl Miller)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed1a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed1a/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contributed Talks 1b: Mostly Theory (Chairs: Omar Fawzi and Carl Miller)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed1b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed1b/</guid><description>Download the chat.</description></item><item><title>Contributed Talks 2a: Experiments: QKD and beyond (Chairs: Qiang Zhang and Vadim Makarov)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed2a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed2a/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contributed Talks 2b: Device independence: theory and experiment (Chairs: Qiang Zhang and Vadim Makarov)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed2b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed2b/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contributed Talks 3: QKD: Security proofs and experiments (Chairs: Roger Colbeck and Li Qian)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contributed Talks 4a: Random-number generation (Chairs: Felix Bussieres and Hugo Zbinden)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed4a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed4a/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contributed Talks 4b: Experimental QKD (Chairs: Felix Bussieres and Hugo Zbinden)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed4b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed4b/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contributed Talks 5a: Encryption and coin-flipping (Chairs: Sevag Gharibian and Or Sattath)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed5a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed5a/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contributed Talks 5b: Post-quantum security (Chairs: Sevag Gharibian and Or Sattath)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed5b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/contributed5b/</guid><description/></item><item><title>End of Day + Q&amp;A + networking</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/__endofday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/__endofday/</guid><description>Lunch and Coffee is served over in our virtual Meet &amp;amp; Greet Room . The speakers from the last session are available for an after-talk chat at the tables.</description></item><item><title>Industry Session (Chairs: Christoph Marquardt and Akihisa Tomita)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/industrial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/industrial/</guid><description>Speakers Cheng-Zhi Peng, University of Science and Technology of China Andreas Poppe, AIT, OpenQKD Hao Qin, CAS Quantum Network Yoshimichi Tanizawa, Toshiba Martin Ward, Toshiba Research, ETSI Program PART I : Standardization Activities 11:00-11:15 Hao Qin (CAS Quantum Network) ITU-T and ISO slides 11:15-11:30 Martin Ward (Toshiba Research Lab. UK) ETSI slides PART II: Projects for QKD network around the world 11:30-11:45 Cheng-Zhi Peng (USTC) China slides 11:45-12:00 Andreas Poppe (AIT) OpenQKD (EU) slides 12:00-12:15 Yoshimichi Tanizawa (Toshiba) SIP and Global QCN (Japan)</description></item><item><title>Invited: Experimental Sending-or-Not-Sending Twin-Field Quantum Key Distribution over 509 km (Chairs: Roger Colbeck and Li Qian)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_liu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_liu/</guid><description>Abstract: Channel loss is one of the most severe limitation to extend the transmission distance of quantum key distribution in practice, given that quantum signals cannot be amplified. Many efforts have been made towards the goal of achieving longer-distance QKD. In long terms, quantum repeater-based quantum network may provide an ultimate solution; In short term, both theoretical and experimental progress are made to distribute secure keys in longer distance in practical situation.</description></item><item><title>Invited: Quantum key distribution with correlated sources (Chairs: Roger Colbeck and Li Qian)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_pereira/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_pereira/</guid><description>Abstract: In theory, quantum key distribution (QKD) offers information-theoretic security. In practice, however, it does not, due to the discrepancies between the assumptions used in the security proofs and the behaviour of the real apparatuses. Recent years have witnessed a tremendous effort to fill the gap, being the treatment of correlations among pulses a major elusive problem. Here, we close this gap by introducing a simple yet general method to prove the security of QKD with arbitrarily long range pulse correlations.</description></item><item><title>Invited: Quantum zero-knowledge from Locally Simulatable Proofs (Chair: Margarida Pereira)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_grilo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_grilo/</guid><description>Abstract: On a zero-knowledge protocol, Alice proves the truth of some statement (e.g. graph is 3-colorable, graph isomorphism, etc.) to Bob in such a way that he does not learn anything else than the truth of the statement. As paradoxical as it may sound, there are several proposals for zero-knowledge protocols in the classical setting and they have far-reaching applications in cryptography. Recently, there has been some effort on proposing new zero-knowledge protocols for quantum statements, but a long-standing open question is the existence of simple &amp;ldquo;commit-and-open&amp;rdquo; protocols for such a task.</description></item><item><title>Invited: Security proofs for continuous-variable quantum key distribution (Chair: Frédéric Dupuis)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_leverrier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_leverrier/</guid><description>Abstract: Continuous variables are attracting a lot of attention lately in the quantum cryptography community thanks to their good compatibility with telecom standards. In order to improve implementations, however, it appears fruitful to deviate from the original &amp;ldquo;all-Gaussian&amp;rdquo; protocols and to rely instead on encodings on discrete consellations of coherent states. While beneficial from an implementation viewpoint, this modification raises a number of difficulties when it comes to proving the security of the protocol.</description></item><item><title>Invited: Speeding-up QKD and downsizing QRNGs (Chair: Louis Salvail)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_bussieres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_bussieres/</guid><description>Abstract: In this talk I will first cover some of our recent QKD progress towards increasing the reach and key rate using superconducting nanowires single-photon detectors designed specifically to optimise these goals. In a second part I will present the principle behind ID Quantique’s QRNG chip, which is now deployed in mobiles phones. I will discuss how its entropy output is modelled and guaranteed to provide solid grounds for this mass-market security application.</description></item><item><title>Invited: Towards quantum repeater and network with cold atoms (Chair: Christian Majenz)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_bao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/invited_bao/</guid><description>Abstract: Quantum internet will enable a number of revolutionary applications, such as distributed quantum computing, large scale quantum communication and cooperative operation of atomic clocks. Cold atomic ensembles are a very promising approach for quantum internet, featuring long coherence time and collectively enhanced interaction with single photons. The current central theme in this direction is to improve the performance of fundamental building blocks and to construct small-scale networks which go beyond state of the art.</description></item><item><title>Lunch + Q&amp;A + networking</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/__lunch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/__lunch/</guid><description>Lunch and Coffee is served over in our virtual Meet &amp;amp; Greet Room . The speakers from the last session are available for an after-talk chat at the tables.</description></item><item><title>Opening</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/open/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/open/</guid><description>Welcome everybody!</description></item><item><title>Poster Session 1</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/poster1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/poster1/</guid><description>This poster session takes place on Tue, 11 Aug, 15:15 - 17:15 over at our virtual Meet &amp;amp; Greet Room .
PDF instructions for poster presenters Posters presented in this session Universal limitations on quantum key distribution over a network Siddhartha Das (École polytechnique de Bruxelles, Université libre de Bruxelles); Stefan Bäuml (ICFO-Institut de Ciencies Fotoniques, The Barcelona Institute of Science and Technology); Marek Winczewski (National Quantum Information Centre in Gdańsk, University of Gdańsk); Karol Horodecki (International Centre for Theory of Quantum Technologies, University of Gdańsk) [abstract] Abstract: Entanglement is an intriguing quantum phenomenon with crucial implications for both fundamental physics and technological applications, e.</description></item><item><title>Poster Session 2</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/poster2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/poster2/</guid><description>PDF instructions for poster presenters Floorplan for this session This poster session takes place on Thu, 13 Aug, 11:00 - 13:00 over at our virtual Meet &amp;amp; Greet Room . The floor numbers are indicated at the posters below.
Posters presented in this session Twin-field quantum digital signatures Chun-Hui Zhang (Nanjing University of Posts and Telecommunications); Yu-Teng Fan (Nanjing University of Posts and Telecommunications); Chun-Mei Zhang (Nanjing University of Posts and Telecommunications); Guang-Can Guo (Nanjing University of Posts and Telecommunications); Qin Wang (Nanjing University of Posts and Telecommunications) [abstract] Abstract: At present, the performance of quantum digital signatures (QDSs) is limited by key generation protocols (e.</description></item><item><title>Start of Day + networking</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/__startofday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/__startofday/</guid><description>Breakfast, Lunch and Coffee is served over in our virtual Meet &amp;amp; Greet Room . You are welcome to have a chat and network before the official program starts.</description></item><item><title>Tutorial: Enabling technologies for quantum networks (Chair: Vadim Makarov)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/tutorial_awschalom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/tutorial_awschalom/</guid><description>Due to legal restrictions, no recording of David&amp;rsquo;s talk but only his slides will be available.</description></item><item><title>Tutorial: New results on Symmetric Quantum Cryptanalysis and Perspectives (Chair: Frédéric Dupuis)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/tutorial_naya/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/tutorial_naya/</guid><description>Abstract: During this talk we will introduce the context and summarize the state-of-the-art of the main quantum symmetric cryptanalysis results, providing the details of some particularly interesting cases. We will also present the scenario of some related open problems that are yet to be solved or improved.</description></item><item><title>Tutorial: Practical aspects of quantum key distribution systems and beyond (Chair: Norbert Lütkenhaus)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/tutorial_diamanti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/tutorial_diamanti/</guid><description>Abstract: In this tutorial talk, we will present the current landscape in quantum key distribution, focusing on the practical aspects of the most prominent technologies. We will highlight the main challenges for the miniaturization of such systems and for their integration into telecommunication networks, and discuss prospects for long-distance operation in both optical fibre and satellite-based links aiming at a global quantum communication infrastructure. We will also touch upon implementations of quantum cryptographic protocols beyond QKD, and discuss possible use cases for QKD and other protocols in various scenarios of interest in terms of performance and trust requirements, emphasizing the efforts required for the industrialization of the underlying technology.</description></item><item><title>Tutorial: Security of quantum key distribution: approach from complementarity (Chair: Christoph Hirche)</title><link>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/tutorial_koashi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://competent-nightingale-85ae87.netlify.com/sessions/tutorial_koashi/</guid><description>Abstract: In this tutorial talk, I will explain about one branch of proof techniques for the security of QKD, which is based on counting the number of phase errors. It dates back to the first security proofs for the BB84 protocol by Mayers and by Shor and Preskill. Since then, it has gradually extended its applicability to other QKD protocols. Here the “phase” refers to an observable complementary to the “bit” forming the key.</description></item></channel></rss>